Guide to the Donald W. Baker College Veterinary Medicine Photograph Collection, 1950- 1969.
Baker, Donald W. College Veterinary Medicine Photograph Collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Donald W. Baker College Veterinary Medicine Photograph Collection, 1950- 1969.
24-2-4215
Baker, Donald Wyckoff,
4.5 cubic ft.
Photographs
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection of photographs mostly pertaining to the Veterinary School at Cornell showing faculty, staff, facilities, students, classes, events, and other topics documenting operations in the College.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor Donald Wyckoff Baker, D.V.M., Ph.D. (1899-1978) was Director of the Diagnostic Laboratory (1928-1933), Assistant Professor (1933) of Parasitology, Associate Professor (1940), Professor (1947), and Professor Emeritus (1965) at the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine. As such, he became the first Professor of Parasitology at the College. Over a span of 37 years, Dr. Baker was "devoted to people, the Veterinary College, and Cornell University" as a frequent traveler, speaker at hundreds of meetings, author of scientific papers, and consulting veterinarian. As a teacher, "he chose to emphasize the problem that parasitism presented to the clinician."
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection of photographs mostly pertaining to the Veterinary School at Cornell. The photographs are almost entirely taken by Baker. Some subjects extend beyond the Vet School to other areas of Cornell. The photographs show faculty, staff, facilities, students, classes, events, and other topics documenting operations in the College.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Baker, Donald Wyckoff, 1899-1978; Cornell University. College of Veterinary Medicine.; New York State College of Veterinary Medicine -- Faculty.; New York State College of Veterinary Medicine -- Students.; New York State College of Veterinary Medicine -- Alumni and alumnae.; New York State College of Veterinary Medicine.
Subjects:
Veterinary medicine -- New York (State) -- Ithaca.; Veterinary medicine -- Study and teaching.; Veterinarians.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Note on Boxes:
Boxes 5a, 5b, 5c, and 5d are smaller-sized boxes housed within Box 5.
CONTAINER LIST
- John Stack and Robert Stack (Box 1, Folder VPC.00001)
  Description: John Stack and Robert Stack, class of 1950, at commencement.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 5" x 7", 1 print on paper
- Dr. William F. Stack, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00002)
  Description: William F. Stack, Class of 1953, giving a demonstration in front of a tree. Cars and a slide in the background.
- Arthur Trayford, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00003)
  Description: Arthur Trayford in a sporty hat, looking right, possibly at a stop watch or camera
  Size and Number of Photographs: 10" x 10", 1 print on paper
- Cane, Trayford and McClelland (Box 1, Folder VPC.00004)
  Description: Candid of Cane '35, Arthur Trayford, Robert B. McClelland
  Size and Number of Photographs: 9.5" x 9.5", 3 prints on cardboard, 1 print on paper
- Arthur Trayford (Box 1, Folder VPC.00005)
  Description: Candid of Arthur Trayford, class of 1927, standing with mouth open in front of a podium
  Size and Number of Photographs: 5" x 10", 2 print on paper
- Arthur Trayford, 1955 (Box 1, Folder VPC.00006)
  Description: Candid of Arthur Trayford looking to the right at the 47th Annual Conference, 1955.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 6" x 10.5", 1 print on paper
- Donald A. Boardman, 1955 (Box 1, Folder VPC.00007)
  Description: Candid of Donald A. Boardman, looking left, with a lamp behind him. Wearing 47th Annual Conference name tag.
- Arthur Thiele with new meat inspectors, 1956 (Box 1, Folder VPC.00008)
  Description: Caption reads: "Dr. Arthur Thiele in the Inspectors Office with his class of neophyte lay meat inspectors. Topic for the afternoon - lymph glands and…, October 1956."
- Art Paddock and Leonard Tyler, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00009)
  Description: Candid of Art Paddock, class of 1921 and Leonard Tyler, class of 1930 smoking cigarettes on steps
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7" x 8", 1 print on cardboard
- John Bentinck-Smith, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00010)
  Description: Candid of John Bentinck-Smith, reading something on a clip board hanging from a bulletin board
  Size and Number of Photographs: 8" x 10", 1 print on cardboard
- William F. Stack and Jack Hyde, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00010a)
  Description: William F. Stack, Class of 1953, and Jack Hyde, Class of 1954, sitting at a table. Stack is holding a cigarette.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7" x 9" & 10" x 10", 2 prints on paper (one cropped)
- Francis Fox, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00011)
  Description: Francis Fox standing outside, wearing alight summer suit.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 2" x 8", 1 print on paper
- Louise Barr, John Bentinck-Smith, and unidentified woman, 1964 (Box 5a, Folder VPC.00012)
  Description: Louise Barr, John Bentinck-Smith, and unidentified woman. See also VPC.00286
  Size and Number of Photographs: no prints
- Edgar "Brud Tucker and Clem Angstrom, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00013)
  Description: Edgar "Brud" Tucker (right) and Clem Angstrom in front of the New York State Veterinary College Regional Laboratory.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 5" x 7", 2 prints on paper
- A.G. Danks, ca. 1940s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00014)
  Description: Arthur Gordon Danks standing outside. Appears to be holding a bucket.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 10" x 10" 8" x 9", 2 prints on paper
- Stephen Roberts, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00015)
  Description: Candid of Stephen J. Roberts, class of 1938, showing a film.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 6.5" x 9", 2 prints on cardboard
- Dr. and Mrs. Allen Goss, 1962 (Box 1 and 5a, Folder VPC.00016)
  Description: Candid of Dr. and Mrs. Allen Goss at a New York State Veterinary Medical Society meeting. Mrs. Goss is seated while Dr. Goss is half-seated with his arm around her
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7.5" x 9.5" 3" x 5", 1 print on cardboard, 2 prints on paper"
- Dr. and Mrs. Hartenstein, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00017)
  Description: Candid of Dr. Chet Hartenstein and his wife at a New York State Veterinary Medical Society meeting. He is holding a pipe
  Size and Number of Photographs: 8" x 10", 1 print on paper
- Dr. and Mrs. Albert Beck, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00018)
  Description: Candid of Dr. and Mrs. Albert Beck, Class of 1959, at a picnic drinking Utica Club beer. She's wearing a hat
  Size and Number of Photographs: 8" x 10", 2 prints on paper (one cropped), 1 print on cardboard (cropped)"
- Stephen Roberts and unidentified man, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00019)
  Description: Candid of Stephen Roberts, class of 1938 and unidentified man holding a hat and a cigarette
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7" x 10", 1 print on paper 1 transparency"
- Mrs. Stephen J. Roberts, Clara Gage, Peter Olafson and Dr. Wagner, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00020)
  Description: Candid of, left to right, Mrs. Stephen J. Roberts, Clara Gage, Peter Olafson and Dr. Wagner. Clara Gage is bending over a table.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 8" x 10", 5" x 6", 1 print on paper (cropped), 2 prints on cardboard (1 cropped)"
- Mia Rienap and Dr. and Mrs. George Lawrence, 1960 (Box 1, Folder VPC.00021)
  Description: Candid of Mia Rienap and Dr. and Mrs. George Lawrence at the old circulation desk in the Schurman Hall library. Reinap has her back to the camera.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 5" x 8", 3" x 5", 2 prints on paper
- Drs Knapp and McEwen, 1956 (Box 1, Folder VPC.00022)
  Description: Caption reads: "Dr. Knapp and Dr. McEwen examining beef and sheep livers slaughtered at Moneton, N.B. for presence of lancet liver flukes, Nov. 19, 1956"
  Size and Number of Photographs: 10" x 10", 1 print on cardboard
- Choir, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00023)
  Description: An all-male choir
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7.5" x 9, 1 print on paper
- Honor Day recipients 1959, 1959 (Box 1, Folder VPC.00024)
  Description: 10 Honor Day recipients, 1959
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7.5" x 9.5", 3 prints on cardboard
- Peter Olafson and Dorsey Bruner, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00025)
  Description: Candid of Peter Olafson and Dorsey Bruner at commencement in caps and gowns.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7" x 7.5", 2 prints on cardboard
- Fred Schultz, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00026)
  Description: Candid of Fred Schutz, class of 1933, wearing glasses, looking left.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 5" x 10", 1 print on paper
- John Bentinck-Smith and conference attendees, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00027)
  Description: "Candid of John Bentinck-Smith demonstrating in a lab before continuing education class? Can't be Annual Conference - short sleeves. Carlisle W. Van Deusen, class of 1944, is visible standing at far end of desk wearing glasses and a bow tie. See also VPC"
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7.5" x 9.5", 2 prints on cardboard
- Ellis P. Leonard, 1962 (Box 1, Folder VPC.00028)
  Description: Candid of Ellis P. Leonard, class of 1934, and David Covitz, Class of 1963. Leonard is leaning forward, all in white.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7" x 9", 3" x 5", 8" x 10", 1 print on cardboard (cropped), 2 prints on paper"
- Dr. Baker's "Veterinary College Exhibit of the Week", ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00029)
  Description: An exhibit in a classroom teaching entitled "Demonstration of the Parasites of Domestic Animals, by Course 200." 2 students in the picture--one looking at slides, other using magnifying glass
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7" x 10", 3 prints on paper
- Dr. Wiswall and Dr. Crane, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00030)
  Description: Candid of Dr. George Wiswall and Dr. Crane, standing in front of a fire hose, both with hats in hand.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7.5" x 8", 1 print on cardboard
- Duncan ?? and Miles Markham, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00031)
  Description: Duncan ?? and Miles Markham standing in front of a truck. One of them is smoking a cigarette and the other has his hands on his hips
  Size and Number of Photographs: 6" x 7.5", 1 print on cardboard
- D. D. Delanhanty (Box 1 and 5a, Folder VPC.00032)
  Description: D. D. Delanhanty, class of 1947 with a camel
  Size and Number of Photographs: 5" x 7", 3" x 5", 1 print on cardboard, 1 print on paper
- R. R. Birch and unidentified man, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00033)
  Description: R. R. Birch and unidentified man standing outside. Both are wearing hats. Birch is on the left in a white suit
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7.5" x 8.5", 1 print on cardboard
- Robert Garcia, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00034)
  Description: Candid of Robert Garcia, an assistant to Dr. Donald W. Baker, using a microscope
- Mia Reinap, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00035)
  Description: Mia Rienap, Librarian, sorting through papers.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 8" x 8.5", 1 print on cardboard
- Gumaer, Speigel and McConnel, ca. 1940s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00036)
  Description: Kenneth Gumaer (class of 1943), Spiegel, George McConnell (class of 1929) and 1 unidentified man on the steps of the New York State Veterinary College Regional Laboratory
  Size and Number of Photographs: 5" x 7" 3" x 5", 2 prints on paper
- Drs. Bixby and Brown, 1956 (Box 1, Folder VPC.00037)
  Description: Donald Bixby, Class of 1935, and Albert Brown, Class of 1915, at 48th Annual Conference. Both are seated and leaning forward. Brown has a cigar.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7.5" x 8", 3 prints on cardboard (2 cropped), 1 transparency"
- Medicine Building, ca. 1940s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00038)
  Description: Medicine building, Old Vet campus
  Size and Number of Photographs: 9.5" x 12", 1 print on paper
- James A Baker and Bruce Widger, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00039)
  Description: Dewitt "Dutch" Baker, Class of 1944, and Bruce Widger, Class of 1951, at a conference dinner table.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7" x 9.5", 1 print on paper
- George and Edith Poppensiek, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00040)
  Description: George and Edith Poppensiek at a conference dinner table
  Size and Number of Photographs: 8" x 10", 3 prints on paper
- Frank McClelland Jr., Robert McClelland, John McCormick, Raymond Burchard, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00041)
  Description: "Left to right: Frank McClelland Jr, class of 1940, Robert McClelland, class of 1934, John McCormick, class of 1949, Raymond Burchard, class of 1949 All are standing outside with overcoats and hats in front of a door"
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7.5" x 9.5", 4 prints on cardboard
- David Hopkins with a horse, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00042)
  Description: David Hopkins with a horse nibbling on his jacket.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7.5" x 9", 1 print on cardboard
- Dr. Tasker, ca. 1961 (Box 1, Folder VPC.00043)
  Description: Candid of John Tasker leaning back at desk.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 8" x 10", 3" x 5", 3 prints on paper
- John Bentinck-Smith giving a demonstration, ca. 1960s (Box 1 and 5a, Folder VPC.00044)
  Description: John Bentinck-Smith giving a demonstration in the lab. Probably continuing education. He is holding up two fingers. See also VPC.00027.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 8" x 10", 2 prints on paper
- H. L. Gilman, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00045)
  Description: Candid of H. L. Gilman standing outside talking to a man with back turned to the camera
  Size and Number of Photographs: 4.5" x 5.5", 1 print on paper
- H. L. Gilman, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00046)
  Description: H. L. Gilman with packages, wearing his coat, standing in front of a fireplace
- Class of 1963 group laughing on a lawn, 1962 (Box 1 and 5a, Folder VPC.00047)
  Description: Group from Class of 1963 posed on a lawn. Dick Sheehan, class of 1963 is in the back row left with glasses. See also VPC.00295, VPC.00296 and VPC.00297.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 6" x 10", 3 prints on paper
- H. L. Gilman, ca. 1960s (Box 1 and 5a, Folder VPC.00048)
  Description: Formal portrait of H. L. Gilman, class of 1917, seated at his desk with hands clasped.
  Photographer (if other than Baker): John F. Brock
- H. L. Gilman, ca. 1960s (Box 1 and 5a, Folder VPC.00049)
  Description: Formal portrait of H. L. Gilman, class of 1917, seated at his desk writing.
- Mildred Zien, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00050)
  Description: Mildred Zien collecting cash at an Annual Conference
- John Jansen, James Fremont Shigley and unidentified man, 1960 (Box 1, Folder VPC.00051)
  Description: John F. Jansen, James Fremont Shigley (both Class of 1915) and unidentified man. The three are sitting in chairs facing the camera. A small picture of James Law is behind them.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 5" x 7" 3" x 5", 3 prints on paper
- John Graves and Robert Kirk, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00052)
  Description: Candid of Dr. John "Jack" Graves and Robert W. Kirk
  Size and Number of Photographs: 4" x 6", 3.5" x 7" (cropped and enlarged), 4 prints on paper [3 with Kirk cropped out ]
- Miles Markham, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00053)
  Description: Candid of Miles Markham and 2 unidentified woman at a dinner party
  Size and Number of Photographs: 4" x 8", 7.5" x 9.5, 5" x 8", 3 prints on paper (cropped), 2 prints on cardboard"
- Mrs. Larry Conlon and Mrs. J. Lowe, 1964 (Box 1 and 5a, Folder VPC.00054)
  Description: Candid of Mrs. Larry Conlon and Mrs. J. Lowe seated at a restaurant table. See also VPC.00299
  Size and Number of Photographs: 8" x 10", 5" x 8" (cropped), 3" x 5", 3 prints on paper (1 cropped)
- students examining a sheep, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00055)
  Description: 4 unidentified students examining sheep on a table
  Size and Number of Photographs: 9" x 7.5", 3 prints on cardboard
- C. L. Zymet, N. Heacock, R. O. Jacoby and a dog, 1962 (Box 1, Folder VPC.00056)
  Description: C. L. Zymet, N. Heacock, R. O. Jacoby, all Class of 1963, with a dog outside the small animal clinic
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7.5" x 9.5", 3" x 5", 2 prints on cardboard, 1 print on paper
- C. L. Zymet, N. Heacock, R. O. Jacoby and a dog, 1962 (Box 1, Folder VPC.00057)
  Description: C. L. Zymet, N. Heacock, R. O. Jacoby, all Class of 1963, with a dog outside the small animal clinic. See also VPC.00476.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 3" x 5", 1 print on paper
- Dean Poppensiek and students at Class of 1961 picnic, 1961 (Box 1 and 5a, Folder VPC.00058)
  Description: Candid of Dean Poppensiek and students at Class of 1961 picnic
  Size and Number of Photographs: 9" x 7.5", 3" x 5", 2 prints on cardboard, 1 print on paper
- Dr. D. E. Hughes, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00059)
  Description: Candid of D. E. Hughes about to make speech at an Annual Conference. He's wearing a microphone.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 6" x 8", 1 print on paper
- Sid Martin, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00060)
  Description: Sid Martin in coveralls and rubber boots about to walk into a barn
- Robert McClelland and group, ca. 1940s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00061)
  Description: Candid of Robert McClelland, class of 1934 (2nd from the left), and unidentified group standing outside peering in a box with a horse painted on it.
- Student-Faculty Picnic, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00062)
  Description: Softball Game in Stewart Park at the Faculty-Senior Picnic--18 students and faculty in the distance
- George McConnell, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00063)
  Description: George McConnell, class of 1929
  Size and Number of Photographs: 4.5" x 7", 3.5" x 4.5", 3 prints on paper
- John Bentinck-Smith, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00064)
  Description: Candid of John Bentinck-Smith, Class of 1944
  Size and Number of Photographs: 5" x 8", 5" x 7", 2 prints on paper
- Dr. Tice with 2 unidentified men, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00065)
  Description: Candid of 2 unidentified men and Dr. Ken Tice, Class of 1935 (on the right)
- Frank S. Graziadei, 1955 (Box 1, Folder VPC.00066)
  Description: Candid of Frank S. Graziadei, class of 1929, with unidentified man smoking a pipe, at the 47th Annual Conference, January 1955.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 9.5" x 9.5" and 7.5" x 9.5", 1 print on paper, 1 print on cardboard
- Dave Armstrong and Dave Hopkins, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00067)
  Description: Candid of Dave Armstrong and David Hopkins, both class of 1930
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7.5" x 9.5", 1 print on paper
- W. S. Stone and O. E. Helms, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00068)
  Description: Candid of W. S. Stone, class of 1935 and O. E. Helms, class of 1920. Stone has his mouth full.
- Student picnic, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00069)
  Description: Sharp, Herr and R.E. Treat at a student picnic. Treat, Class of 1962, is wearing an apron.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 8" x 10", 5" x 9", 1 print on paper, 2 prints on cardboard"
- Earl Markham and Robert Hlllman, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00070)
  Description: Candid of Earl S. Markham, Class of 1912, and Robert Hillman, class of 1955. Markham has a cigar. Hillman is in coveralls. There's a door and a brick wall behind them.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7" x 8", 1 print on particle board
- Don Boardman Sr., ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00071)
  Description: Candid of Don Boardman Sr.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 10" x 10", 7.5" x 9", 1 print on paper, 1 print on cardboard
- Seth Johnson and unidentified woman, ca. 1960s (Box 1 and 5a, Folder VPC.00072)
  Description: Seth Johnson and unidentified woman looking at a card /paper at a dinner table
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7.5" x 9.5", 1 print on cardboard
- John McCarthy, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00073)
  Description: Candid of John McCarthy, Class of 1934, from Cortland standing by a car scratching a dog
  Size and Number of Photographs: 5.5" x 8", 1 print on cardboard
- Dr. William Shaw, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00074)
  Description: Candid of Dr. William Shaw
  Size and Number of Photographs: 4.5" x 8", 1 print on cardboard
- A. W. Wright and 3 unidentified men, 1963 (Box 1 and 5a, Folder VPC.00075)
  Description: Candid of A. W. Wright (far left), and 3 unidentified man at 25th Reunion of the Class of 1938. There are eagles on the wallpaper in the background. See also VPC.00119, VPC.00147, VPC.00159, VPC.00477, and VPC.00478
  Size and Number of Photographs: "7"" x 9.5"" 3"" x 5", 2 prints on cardboard, 1 print on paper
- Hadley C. Stephenson, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00076)
  Description: Hadley C. Stephenson standing in a doorway in hat and coat with a cigarette in his mouth
  Size and Number of Photographs: 9" x 11.5", 1 print on paper
- Students in a field, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00077)
  Description: 2 students and a hunter watching a Mew York State Conservation Department person examine a dead deer. They are standing in front of a Conservation Department truck. It has a board hanging from it with examples of jaw bones.
- Clarence Preston and Arthur Johnson, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00078)
  Description: Clarence Preston and Arthur Johnson standing outside what looks like Schurman Hall.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 8.5" x 9", 1 print on paper
- Dr. Wooden and others examining a sheep, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00079)
  Description: Candid of Dr. Aubrey Wooden, class of 1923 and others examining a sheep
- D. Bixby, Kaley, unidentified woman, Al Brown, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00080)
  Description: Donald Bixby, class of 1935; Grant Kaley, Class of 1931; unidentified woman, and Albert Brown, Class of 1915, at an Annual Conference dinner party. Same event is pictured in VPC.00302 and VPC.00707-00710.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 6.5" x 9", 1 print on cardboard
- Howard K Fuller, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00081)
  Description: Candid of Howard K. "Cap" Fuller, class of 1932, at an Annual Conference
- Miles Markham and unidentified man, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00082)
  Description: Candid of Miles Markham (on the right) and unidentified man in front of a truck. Markham is smoking a cigarette. The unidentified man is wearing a bolo tie.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 8.5" x 11", 1 print on paper
- Janette McEntee, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00083)
  Description: Janette McEntee standing outside next to an awning. Her hands are in her coat and she's carrying a purse.
- Unidentified man, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00084)
  Description: Candid of Stewart Wright, looking down and right. Holding paper in his hand, 2 pens in his pocket
  Size and Number of Photographs: "8.5"" x 9"" 10" x 10", 1 print on cardboard, 1 print on paper
- 1961 JAVMA Picnic, 1961 (Box 1 and 5a, Folder VPC.00085)
  Description: 1961 JAVMA Picnic, log sawing contest.. See also VPC.00292 and VPC.00092
  Size and Number of Photographs:, no prints
- Peter Olafson and the Schultz's, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00086)
  Description: Candid of Peter Olafson with the Schultz's
  Size and Number of Photographs: 8" x 10" 5" x 7", 3 prints on paper (one cropped)
- Dr. and Mrs. Gerald Ward, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00087)
  Description: Dr. and Mrs. Gerald Ward (class of 1949) at a dinner party. He is wearing glasses and looking at her. She is looking at the camera and wearing a pin on her left shoulder.
  Size and Number of Photographs: 7.5" x 9.5", 1 print on paper, 1 print on cardboard
- Racheal Gordon Krieger, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00088)
  Description: Racheal Gordon Krieger standing outside wearing a coat. She is dabbing at her eyes
  Size and Number of Photographs: 4" x 8", 1 print on paper
- Peter Olafson and Harold Nadler, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder VPC.00089)
  Description: Candid of (left to right): Peter Olafson, Class of 1926, and Harold Nadler
  Size and Number of Photographs: 8" x 10" 5.5"" x 7.5""", 2 prints on paper (one cropped)